Guide to the Greek Life Office Records 1918-2015
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center
- Publications, 1971-2015; Series 8
  - Newsletters, 1977-2010 (Box-folder 7.29-7.32)
    4 folders. There is no content for the years 1993 through 2001.
  - Newsletters, 1983-1999 (Box-folder 10.6)
  - Posters, 1983-2008 (Box-folder 10.7)
- Surveys, 1970-2009; Series 9
  Series 9 documents survey activity gauging student opinion about participation in rush activities, general perceptions of the OSU Greek community, and chapter finances.
  - AFA/EBI (Association of Fraternity Advisors; Educational Benching Inc.) Fraternity/Sorority Assessment Survey, 2009 (Box-folder 7.33-7.35)
  - Chapter Financial Survey, 2005 (Box-folder 7.36)
  - Chapter Participation and Attendance Compilation for 2005-2006 (Box-folder 7.37)
  - Fraternity Pre-recruitment Survey, 2000 (Box-folder 7.38)
  - Fraternity Rush Evaluation, 1998 (Box-folder 7.39)
  - Freshmen Who Did Not Participate in Rush Week Poll, 1970 (Box-folder 7.40)
  - Greek Assessment Survey #1, 2000 (Box-folder 7.41)
  - Greek Conversation Feedback, 2000 (Box-folder 7.42)
  - Greek Life 101 Class Project Surveys, 2001 (Box-folder 7.43)
  - Greek Life Assessment Surveys, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 7.44)
  - Matriculation Surveys, 2000 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - National Headquarters Risk Management Assessment Surveys, 2002; 2006 (Box-folder 8.2-8.3)
    2 folders
  - New Member Education Program Time Line Survey, 2003 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - OSU Greek Image Survey, 2003 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Rush Orientation Survey, undated (Box-folder 8.6)
  - Survey of Greek Life at Other Universities, 2007 (Box-folder 8.7)
  - Untitled Survey, undated (Box-folder 8.8)
- Speeches and Presentations, 2000-2015; Series 10
  Series 10 is made up of scripts of speeches and presentations and slide shows presented at annual Greek matriculation ceremonies, the centennial celebration of Greek Life at OSU, and various other events.
  - Centennial Banquet Script, 2015 (Box-folder 8.9)
  - Matriculation Ceremony Scripts, 2004-2012 (Box-folder 8.10)
  - Matriculation Ceremonies, 2005-2006
    This folder consists of 4 born digital files documenting the 2005 and 2006 Greek Matriculation ceremonies. The file reflecting the 2005 ceremony is a Word file containing the presentation script for Director of Greek Life Robert Kerr, while the other three are made up of moving image files of the 2006 ceremony. These files are available for viewing in the Reading Room.
  - Slide Shows, 2007-2008
    This digital folder contains 362 images incorporated into 2 slide shows created for the 2007 and 2008 Greek Matriculation ceremonies, respectively. The images primarily depict group shots of sorority and fraternity members and views from Greek community events such as the IFC Sing. These files are available for viewing in the Reading Room.
  - Presentations For Various Events, 2000-2015 (Box-folder 8.11)
  - Student Life Program Presentations, 2004 (Box-folder 8.12)
    Presentations by representatives of programs forming the Student Life Leadership Team. Greek Life is one of the programs.
- Event Registration Files, 1999-2007; Series 11
  Series 11 is comprised of registration event lists generated by the Greek Life Office to keep track of events planned by sorority and fraternity chapters. The information includes the house sponsoring the activity, the date, and event title. Other details in the lists relate to the administrative paperwork accepted or required for the event to comply with university policies.
  - Event Registration Files, 1999-2007 (Box-folder 8.13-8.17)
- Subject Files, 1968-2015; Series 12
  Series 12 contains materials collected by Greek Life Office staff for reference and informational purposes. These items include articles, brochures, historical timelines, newspaper clippings, policy statements, reports, and a student paper.
  - Alcohol Education Programming, 1997-2011 (Box-folder 8.18)
  - Alcohol Education Programming, undated (Box-folder 10.8)
  - Alumni Programming and Fundraising For Chapters, circa 2009 (Box-folder 8.19)
  - Awards, 2004-2008 (Box-folder 8.20)
  - Conferences and Workshops, 2002-2011 (Box-folder 8.21)
  - Conflict Management and Resolution, 1998 (Box-folder 8.22)
  - Core Tools, 1984-2007 (Box-folder 8.23)
  - Crowd Control, 2001 (Box-folder 8.24)
  - Diversity, 2003-2010 (Box-folder 8.25)
  - Diversity, 1993 (Box-folder 10.9)
  - Greek History at OSU, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 8.26)
  - Greek Life Models, 1995-2007 (Box-folder 8.27)
  - Hazing, 1975-2010 (Box-folder 8.28)
  - Historical Topics in American Fraternalism, 1976-2001 (Box-folder 8.29)
  - Misconduct Among Greeks, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 8.30)
  - Offensive Fraternity Tee-Shirt Designs, 1998 (Box-folder 10.10)
    Color photocopies.
  - Oregon Administrative Rules, 1999-2006 (Box-folder 8.31)
  - OSU Community Service Center, undated (Box-folder 8.32)
  - Panhellenic Partnership Collaboration, 2009 (Box-folder 8.33)
  - Recruitment, 2006 (Box-folder 8.34)
  - Relations with Universities and Communities, 1988 (Box-folder 8.35)
  - Risk Management, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 8.36)
  - Student Demographic Trends, 2005-2010 (Box-folder 8.37)
  - Student Learning Styles, 2002 (Box-folder 8.38)
  - Student Services Office Administration Information, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 8.39)
- Photographs, 1945-2013; Series 13
  Series 13 is comprised of photographs depicting OSU sorority and fraternity members in group shots, chapter houses, various Greek events, and Greek Life office staff. Many of the photographs had been laminated and mounted in foamcore for display. In total, there are 103 photographic prints in this series.
  - Greek Houses, undated (Box-folder 9.1)
  - Greek Life Staff, 2005 (Box-folder 9.2)
  - Group Shots, 1945-2011 (Box-folder 9.3)
  - Images from the Display "Oregon State Greek Life: 1882-2003", circa 2003 (Box-folder 9.4-9.5)
    Some of the images contain captions with velcro backing. Captions found loose among the images have been collected and placed into a small envelope that is inside one of the folders.
  - Group Shots, 2002-2013 (Box-folder 10.11)
  - Pi Kappa Phi Bike "Journey Across America" Event, 2004 (Box-folder 9.6)
  - Various Greek Events, undated (Box-folder 9.7-9.8)
- Artifacts, 1976-1985; Series 14
  Series 14 is made up of artifacts consisting of two plaques and the "Greek Scruples" card game.
  - Card Game: Greek Scruples, undated; 9.1 (Box-item 9.1)
    Sheets of uncut playing cards and instruction guide housed in an envelope. Developed at the University of Pittsburgh.
  - Plaque: Highest Freshman Class Grade Point Average, 1976-1985; 9.2 (Box-item 9.2)
  - Plaque: Most Improved Fraternity Grade Point Average, 1976-1985; 9.3 (Box-item 9.3)
- Judicial Sanction Files, 1996-2008; Series 15
  Series 15 relates to the outcomes of judicial hearings brought before the Interfraternity Council Judicial Committee and Panhellenic Council. In addition to letters to fraternities and sororities outlining violations and probationary action, these files also include newspaper clippings and copies of risk management policies.
  Access to these files is restricted due to the presence of confidential information. All requests for access to these materials should be directed to the University Archivist.
  - RESTRICTED: Judicial Sanction Files, 1996-2008 (Box-folder 11.1-11.3)